Chris Coenen Collection on General Tom Thumb MS254
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Artifacts, 1750 -- 1996; MS254.000007
  - Slide: Conn. Hist. Soc.: Lavinia just before wedding, 1863; MS254.000306 (Box 12)
    Print, from Brochure, of Lavinia Warren
  - Slide: Conn. Hist. Soc.: Print of Tom and Lavinia with baby, 1864; MS254.000307 (Box 12)
  - Slide: Conn. Hist. Soc.: Print of Tom and Lavinia without the baby, 1864; MS254.000308 (Box 12)
  - Slide: Conn. Hist. Soc.: Nutt and Minnie dancing, 1863; MS254.000309 (Box 12)
  - Slide; Conn. Hist. Soc.; Wedding scene, 1863; MS254.000310 (Box 12)
  - Slide: Conn. Hist. Soc.: Tom and Lifeguards, 1858; MS254.000311 (Box 12)
    From a hand colored stereo by LSC
  - Slide: Bridgeport Public Library: Barnum & Bailey Sideshow Performers, 1920; MS254.000312 (Box 12)
    Gathered performers for the circus
  - Slide: Bridgeport Public Library: Minnie Warren in riding outfit, 1878; MS254.000313 (Box 12)
    She may look pregnant
  - Slide: Bridgeport Public Library: Minnie in dark dress, 1864; MS254.000314 (Box 12)
    Minnie after the wedding
  - Slide: Bridgeport Public Library: Tom in costume, 1860; MS254.000315 (Box 12)
    Tom dressed as Spanish lady
  - Slide: Bridgeport Public Library: Close, Tom in costume, 1860; MS254.000316 (Box 12)
    Close-up
  - Slide: Bridgeport Public Library: Lavinia in the field, 1895; MS254.000317 (Box 12)
    Probably near their home in Middleboro
  - Slide: Bridgeport Public Library: Group, Lavinia, Primo, Ernesto, Lucy and Sarah Adams, 1885; MS254.000318 (Box 12)
    Group of Friends
  - Slide: Bridgeport Public Library: Minnie and friend, 1864; MS254.000319 (Box 12)
    Minnie with unknown man
  - Slide: Bridgeport Public Library: Fancy Minnie, 1864; MS254.000320 (Box 12)
    Minnie by table
  - Slide: Bridgeport Public Library: Tom as Napoleon, 1860; MS254.000321 (Box 12)
  - Slide: Bridgeport Public Library: PT Barnum, 1865; MS254.000322 (Box 12)
    Head shot of Barnum, maybe by Brady
  - Slide: Bridgeport Public Library: Lavinia Warren, 1865; MS254.000323 (Box 12)
    Lavinia by chair
  - Slide: Bridgeport Public Library: Tom in vest with man, 1860; MS254.000324 (Box 12)
    One of his characters
  - Slide: Bridgeport Public Library: Tom as Achilles, 1860; MS254.000325 (Box 12)
    One of his statues
  - Slide: Bridgeport Public Library: Lavinia in plaid dress, 1863; MS254.000326 (Box 12)
    Plaid, quilted dress
  - Slide: Bridgeport Public Library: Tom and friend, 1864; MS254.000327 (Box 12)
    No moustache
  - Slide: Bridgeport Public Library: Tom as Tar, 1858; MS254.000328 (Box 12)
    Tom in character as sailor
  - Slide: Bridgeport Public Library: Tom and man, 1875; MS254.000329 (Box 12)
    Tom with unknown man
  - Poster The Royal Midgets with Jennie Quigley, 1882; MS254.000330 (Box Large Map Case 3 Drawer 3)
    Advertsing broadside for a show featuring the Magris and Jennie Quigley performing at the Opera House
  - Paper doll; Mrs. Tom Thumb; Boston Sunday Post, 1946; MS254.000331 (Box 7)
  - Platter with Barnum's Museum, NY, 1960; MS254.000332 (Box 14)
    Unknown date; Platter with the Currier and Ives print of Broadway
  - French plate with Tom Thumb getting a shave, 1846; MS254.000333 (Box 14)
    Produced in France as part of a set
  - French plate of Tom Thumb in his visiting clothes, 1846; MS254.000334 (Box 14)
  - French plate of Tom Thumb dressed as a Marquis, 1846; MS254.000335 (Box 14)
  - Medal with Victoria dated 1846, MS254.000336 (Box 15)
    Medal probably ordered by Barnum to be sold or given away; some numismatists call this a game
  - Medal with Victoria dated 1850, MS254.000337 (Box 15)
  - Medal with Liberty Bust; no date, 1850; MS254.000338 (Box 15)
  - Medal with Liberty Bust; no date, 1850; MS254.000339 (Box 15)
  - Medal with parents of General Tom Thumb; Strattons, 1844; MS254.000340 (Box 15)
    Cynthia and Sherwood Stratton
  - Medal with Tom Thumb; carriage, 1845; MS254.000341 (Box 15)
    Tom Thumb
  - Medal with Tom Thumb; carriage variation, 1845; MS254.000342 (Box 15)
  - Medal with Comm. Nutt and Minnie Warren, 1865; MS254.000343 (Box 15)
    Nutt and Minnie with birth dates
  - Medal produced in 1881 for circus shows, MS254.000344 (Box 15)
    When Tom and Lavinia travelled with Barnum's circus in 1881, they had medals made; the loop was for a ribbon
  - Medal with Lavinia and Primo Magri; 9th & Arch St. Museum, Philadelphia, 1885; MS254.000345 (Box 15)
    Probably produced by the Museum
  - Mardis Gras Medal with Tom Thumb, 1983; MS254.000346 (Box 15)
    Krewe of Grela with Tom Thumb
  - Small tin plate with General Tom Thumb, 1845; MS254.000347 (Box 15)
    Three inch tin plate with Tom Thumb as Napoleon
  - Tiny French Almanac; !895; Tom Thumb, 1895; MS254.000348 (Box 15)
    One inch "Almanach" with images of Tom Thumb
  - Souvenir Charm; "Somebody's Luggage"; 12 photos, 1865; MS254.000349 (Box 15)
    Produced in England; Twelve mini-photos of Tom, Lavinia, Minnie, Nutt and baby
  - Silver souvenir charm with 12 photos, 1865; MS254.000350 (Box 15)
    Probably English
  - The Liliputian Soap Book; photo of Magris, 1900; MS254.000351 (Box 15)
    Unknown date but circa 1900; advertising; leaves of paper embeded with soap
  - Trivial Pursuit Card with question about Tom Thumb, 1985; MS254.000352 (Box 15)
    Question card from the game Trivial Pursuit
  - Premium card with Tom Thumb; wrong date, 1990; MS254.000353 (Box 15)
    Unknown origin; using Barnum's original fake birth year
  - Ad card for auction of remaining Mrs. Tom Thumb estate, Middleboro, 1930; MS254.000354 (Box 15)
    Auctioning off the remanants of Lavinia's and Count Magris estate; with stereo from sale
  - Tobacco card of Barnum Museum, 1900; MS254.000355 (Box 15)
    Unknown date; copy of early Currier and Ives
  - Cadbury premium; The Miniature Man, 1960; MS254.000356 (Box 15)
    Unknown date; Cadbury card of Tom and Lavinia
  - Matchbook cover; Swedish; Tom Thumb, 1878; MS254.000357 (Box 15)
    Swedish matcb book cover with Tom Thumb
  - Cigarette card; Ripley's; Tomb Thumb kisser, 1960; MS254.000358 (Box 15)
    Unknown date; Ripley's Beleive it or Not card for English cigarettes
  - Tom Thumb doll; 7", 1960; MS254.000359 (Box 15)
    Unknown date; Tom in his later years
  - Tom Thumb Hack Saw Frame; Bridgeport, 1900; MS254.000360 (Box 15)
    Unknown date; Tom as advertising
  - Tom-Pouce, Le Sabot Enchanté ceramic plate, circa 1890; MS254.001396 (Box 14)
  - Tom Thumb circus cut-outs, circa 1920; MS254.001397 (Box 15)
  - Who was General Tom Thumb? A History via Paper Dolls by Tom Tierney, 1986 June; MS254.001398 (Box 15)
  - Stereoscope, circa 1880 -- 1920; MS254.001399 (Object 24)
  - Tom Thumb souvenir spoon, circa 1990; MS254.001421 (Box 15)
  - Circus Hall of Fame View-Master Stereo Pictures, 1957; MS254.001422 (Box 15)
  - Middleborough Tercentennial Celebration and Coin Club of Greater New Bedford wooden coins, 1969; 1992; MS254.001423 (Box 15)
  - "Somebody's Luggage" locket containing wedding photographs of Tom Thumb, circa 1864; MS254.001424 (Box 15)
  - Yellow figurines of man and woman in formal clothing, circa 1950; MS254.001425 (Box 15)
- Cabinet cards, 1850 -- 2010; MS254.000361
  This series contains cabinet cards related to Tom Thumb. Cabinet cards are a type of photograph that is typically mounted on a card. They were most popular in the 1880s and 1890s.
  - Lavinia Warren, Mrs. General Tom Thumb; Putnam, Middleboro, 1880; MS254.000362 (Box 2)
    Portrait of Lavinia by Putnam of Middleboro, Ma.; this photograph was the basis for a woodcut that appeared in periodicals
  - Lavinia Warren, Mrs. General Tom Thumb; by a basket of flowers; Bogardus, NY, 1880; MS254.000363 (Box 2)
    Portrait of Lavinia by Abraham Bogardus, NY; Bogardus was a favored photographer by Tom and Lavinia and did several sittings in the 1880's
  - Tom and Lavinia on balcony; Bogardus, NY; circus hand-outs; 1881; autographed, MS254.000364 (Box 2)
    In 1881, Barnum convinced Tom and Lavinia to travel with his new circus; they had a number of portraits taken by Bogardus for sale at their shows; most are signed and dated
  - Tom and Lavinia on balcony; Bogardus, NY; circus hand-outs; 1881; autographed; II, MS254.000365 (Box 2)
    Variation
  - Tom and Lavinia on balcony; 1881 III, MS254.000366 (Box 2)
  - Tom and Lavinia on balcony; 1881 IV, MS254.000367 (Box 2)
  - Tom and Lavinia on balcony; 1881 V, MS254.000368 (Box 2)
  - Tom and Lavinia on balcony; 1881 VI, MS254.000369 (Box 2)
  - Gen. Tom Thumb and Wife; Bogardus, NY; 1881; autographed, MS254.000370 (Box 2)
    Another portrait by Bogardus that was sold at their shows during the circus tour
  - Gen. Tom Thumb and Wife; Bogardus, NY; 1881; autographed II, MS254.000371 (Box 2)
  - Lavinia Warren, Primo Magri and Ernesto Magri; Eisenmann, NY, 1889; MS254.000372 (Box 2)
    After Charles Stratton's death in 1883, Lavinia married Count Primo Magri in 1885; Charles Eisenmann catered to the dime museum crowd and photographed many of the performers
  - Lavinia Warren, Primo Magri and Ernesto Magri; Eisenmann, NY II, 1889; MS254.000373 (Box 2)
    Variation of 297
  - Lavinia Warren, Primo Magri and Ernesto Magri and manager; Lavinia is holding her favorite pet dog; Eisenmann, NY, 1889; MS254.000374 (Box 2)
    Lavinia's dog travelled with them on tour and sometimes worked in the shows
  - Lavinia Warren, Primo Magri and Ernesto Magri; Eisenmann, NY III, 1889; MS254.000375 (Box 2)
  - Lavinia Warren, Primo Magri and Ernesto Magri; Eisenmann, NY IV, 1889; MS254.000376 (Box 2)
    Variation; holding hands
  - Count and Countess Magri; CR Baker, Detroit, 1888; MS254.000377 (Box 2)
    Probably taken a few years after their marriage; by C R Baker, Detroit, Michigan
  - Mrs. Tom Thumb's Eden Musee Co.; Byarlay, St. Joseph, Mo., 1890; MS254.000378 (Box 2)
    Lavinia and her husband and the Baron formed several traveling "vaudeville" companies. Eden Musee Co. was one of these.
  - Mrs. Tom Thumb's Eden Musee Co.; Byarlay, St. Joseph, Mo.II, 1890; MS254.000379 (Box 2)
  - Mrs. Tom Thumb's Eden Musee Co.; Byarlay, St. Joseph, Mo. III, 1890; MS254.000380 (Box 2)
  - Count Magri, Countess Magri, Baron Magri; Swords Bros., York, Pa., 1892; MS254.000381 (Box 2)
    Swords Bros. took many photos of sideshow performers and others. The Magri Brothers introduce the Countess.
  - Count Magri, Countess Magri, Baron Magri; Swords Bros., York, Pa. II, 1892; MS254.000382 (Box 2)
  - Count Magri, Countess Magri, Baron Magri; Swords Bros., York, Pa. III, 1892; MS254.000383 (Box 2)
  - Count Magri, Countess Magri, Baron Magri; Swords Bros., York, Pa. IV, 1892; MS254.000384 (Box 2)
    Swords Bros. took many photos of sideshow performers and others.
  - Count Magri, Countess Magri, Baron Magri; Swords Bros., York, Pa. V, 1892; MS254.000385 (Box 2)
    Swords Bros. took many photos of sideshow performers.
  - Count Magri, Countess Magri, Baron Magri; Swords Bros., York, Pa.; looking at the book, 1892; MS254.000386 (Box 2)
    The trio looking at a book or album
  - Count Magri, Countess Magri, Baron Magri; Swords Bros., York, Pa. VII, 1892; MS254.000387 (Box 2)
    The Count with his top hat.
  - Count Magri, Countess Magri, Baron Magri; Swords Bros., York, Pa. VIII, 1892; MS254.000388 (Box 2)
    Lavinia holding hands with Primo
  - Count Magri, Countess Magri, Baron Magri; Swords Bros., York, Pa. IX, 1892; MS254.000389 (Box 2)
    Lavinia on top
  - Count Magri, Countess Magri, Baron Magri; Swords Bros., York, Pa. X, 1892; MS254.000390 (Box 2)
    Lavinia on top holding hands with the Count
  - Count Magri, Countess Magri, Baron Magri; Swords Bros., York, Pa. XI, 1892; MS254.000391 (Box 2)
    Lavinia leaning against Primo
  - Count Magri, Countess Magri, Baron Magri; Swords Bros., York, Pa. XII, 1892; MS254.000392 (Box 2)
    Lavinia on bottom leaning against Primo
  - Lavinia and Count Magri; Brown, Barnes and Bell, photographers, UK, 1887; MS254.000393 (Box 2)
    Probably taken on a trip to Europe after their wedding in 1885
  - Count and Countess Magri; Ollivier, NY, 1886; MS254.000394 (Box 2)
    Ollivier was a favorite photographer and they visitd his studios in New York several times
  - Count and Countess Magri; Ollivier, NY II, 1886; MS254.000395 (Box 2)
  - Count and Countess Magri; Ollivier, NY, 1890; MS254.000396 (Box 2)
    Later photo by Ollivier
  - Count and Countess Magri; Ollivier, NY II, 1890; MS254.000397 (Box 2)
  - Count and Countess Magri; Ollivier, NY, 1887; MS254.000398 (Box 2)
    Ollivier photo taken in 1887
  - Count and Countess Magri; Ollivier, NY II, 1887; MS254.000399 (Box 2)
  - Count and Countess Magri; Ollivier, NY III, 1887; MS254.000400 (Box 2)
  - Count and Countess Magri; Ollivier, NY IV, 1887; MS254.000401 (Box 2)
  - Count and Countess Magri; Ollivier, NY; autographed and dated on back; V, 1887; MS254.000402 (Box 2)
    Variation with signatures and date- 1887
  - Count and Countess Magri; Ollivier NY; hair decoration, 1890; MS254.000403 (Box 2)
    Lavinia in bustled dress with hair piece
  - Count & Countess Magri & Bro; Ollivier, NY; autographed on back, 1890; MS254.000404 (Box 2)
    Taken at the same sitting as 328
  - Count and Countess Magri and Ernesto Magri; Ollivier, NY; autographed on back, 1904; MS254.000405 (Box 2)
    Later photo of the trio
  - Count and Countess Magri and Ernesto Magri; Ollivier, NY; labeled in the photo, 1904; MS254.000406 (Box 2)
  - Count and Countess Magri and Ernesto Magri; Olivier NY; signed and dated on the back, 1904; MS254.000407 (Box 2)
    Signed and dated by all three- 1904
  - Primo Magri and Lavinia Warren, 1906; Ollivier, NY; autographed on back; Oakland, Ca., MS254.000408 (Box 2)
    Later photo by Ollivier signed and dated, Oakland, Cal., 1906
  - Lavinia, Primo, Ernesto along with Edwin Newell, Minnie's husband and Annie Nelson; Butman, Middleboro, Ma., 1889; MS254.000409 (Box 2)
    Date is approximate; Minnie Warren married Edwin Newell in 1877; he started performing at a young age and later gained a reputation giving skating exhibitions; Minnie died in childbirth in 1878; Annie Nelson was also a performer
  - Lavinia, Primo, Ernesto along with Edwin Newell, Minnie's husband and Annie Nelson; Butman, Middleboro, Ma., 1889; MS254.000410 (Box 2)
    Variation of 334; probably taken on a visit to Lavinia's home in Middleboro
  - Lavinia, Primo and Ernesto; Harmon, Springvale and Sanford, Me., 1900; MS254.000411 (Box 2)
    Trio in Maine
  - Lavinia, Primo and Ernesto; Gauvin and Gentzel; Halifax, Nova Scotia, 1895; MS254.000412 (Box 2)
    The Trio in Nova Scotia
  - Lavinia, Primo and Ernesto; Gauvin and Gentzel; Halifax, Nova Scotia, 1896; MS254.000413 (Box 2)
    Variation of 337
  - Lavinia, Primo and Ernesto; unknown photographer and location, 1904; MS254.000414 (Box 2)
    Studio shot of the three, probably on tour
  - Lavinia, Primo and Ernesto; unknown photographer and location II, 1904; MS254.000415 (Box 2)
    Variation of 339
  - Lavinia, Primo and Ernesto III, 1904; MS254.000416 (Box 2)
  - Lavinia, Primo and Ernseto; Primo giving Lavinia flowers, 1904; MS254.000417 (Box 2)
    Similar to 339 but Primo is giving flowers to Lavinia
  - Lavinia, Primo and Ernesto; Wilson, Chicago, 1895; MS254.000418 (Box 2)
    Lavinia, Primo and Ernesto; Wilson, Chicago
  - Lavinia, Primo and Ernesto; Wilson,Chicago II, 1895; MS254.000419 (Box 2)
    Variation of 343
  - The Only & Original Mrs. General Tom Thumb; Negretti & Gambra, Crystal Palace, London; signed on back, 1909; MS254.000420 (Box 2)
    The Only & Original Mrs. General Tom Thumb;Negrettti & Gambra, Crystal Palace, London; Lavinia was obsessed with the notion that the public would forget her and her glory days with Tom Thumb, thus there were several attempts in the 1900's to remind the public of her connection to Tom Thumb; autographed on back
  - Lavinia, Primo and Ernesto; Patterson, Chicago; Signed on back by all three, 1904; MS254.000421 (Box 2)
    The Trio taken by Patterson & Co., Chicago; notation on back says "Peoples Theatre, Chicago, Ills, March 24, 1904"; autographed
  - Lavinia, Primo and Ernesto, Chicago, Patterson, 1904; MS254.000422 (Box 2)
    Variation of 346 without the autographs
  - Lavinia, Primo and Ernesto; trimmed card; Garmon, Sanford & Springvale, Me., 1900; MS254.000423 (Box 2)
    Trio on a trip to Maine
  - Lavinia, London Stereoscopic Company, London, 1909; MS254.000424 (Box 2)
    The Company made a trip to Europe in 1909
  - Countess Magri, Nee Mrs. Tom Thumb; Ollivier, NY, 1914; MS254.000425 (Box 2)
    Lavinia trying to remind the public about her past connection to General Tom Thumb
  - Cabinet photo copy of a cdv of Lavinia, Tom and baby, 1864 -- 1870; MS254.000426 (Box 2)
    This is a copy of the cdv with the hoax baby. This one has been significantly re-touched; Tom was not in the original photograph
  - Minnie Warren; Bradley & Rulofson, San Francisco, 1870; MS254.000427 (Box 2)
    Possibly taken as the company began their around the world tour
  - Ernesto and Primo Magri & manager; Bradley & Rulofson, San Francisco, 1878 -- 1881; MS254.000428 (Box 2)
    The Italian midgets came to the US in 1878 and spent several years in California, although they also appear in NYC in 1879
  - Baron Littlefinger, his Family and Count Rosebud his Brother; Ollivier, NY, 1880; MS254.000429 (Box 2)
    Baron Littlefinger (Ernesto) was married and had three children; there was a fourth that died young; the family went back to Italy and never returned; the Baron stayed in the US
  - Baron Littlefinger, His Wife, Children and Brother Count Rosebud; Bradley and Rulofson, San Francisco, 1881; MS254.000430 (Box 2)
    The brothers travelled to Australia and New Zealand in 1881; maybe taken on the way
  - Jennie Quigley; "engaged to Baron Littlefinger", 1887; MS254.000431 (Box 2)
    In one of their acts, the midgets performed a "mock" wedding
  - Composite of Jennie Quigley; Bogardus, NY, 1885 -- 1890; MS254.000432 (Box 2)
    Montage of nine cabinet cards of Jennie by Bogardus
  - Jennie Quigley in costume: Wilson, Chicago, 1890; MS254.000433 (Box 2)
    Jennie in costume for a skit
  - Jennie Quigley; Swift, 1890; MS254.000434 (Box 2)
    Jennie performed for a long time with many companies; dates are approximate
  - Jennie Quigley head shot; Robinson & Roe, Chicago, 1890; MS254.000435 (Box 2)
    Rare close-up of Jennie
  - Royal Midgets, Miss Jennie Quigley; Green and Williams, Cleveland,O., 1883; MS254.000436 (Box 2)
    The three performed together, including the mock mariage
  - Miss Jennie Quigley; autograph and data on back; same pose as 356, 1877; MS254.000437 (Box 2)
    Same cabinet photo as 356 with statistics on back
  - Variation of 362; Royal Midgets and Jennie Quigley, 1883; MS254.000438 (Box 2)
    Taken shortly apart but not the same photograph as 362
  - Lucy and Sarah Adams and Baron Magri; Ollivier, NY, 1883; MS254.000439 (Box 2)
    The Adams sisters were from Martha's Vinyard and were friends of Lavinia; Lucy (1861-1938) and Sarah (1863-1954) performed for a while and then went back to Martha's Vinyard
  - Lucy and Sarah Adams and Baron Magri; Ollivier, NY; variation of 364, 1883; MS254.000440 (Box 2)
    Variation of 364
  - Lucy and Sarah Adams; Eisenmann, NY; signed, 1887; MS254.000441 (Box 2)
    Lucy and Sarah with notations on back; Lucy age 26; Sarah age 24; notations on back are probably written by one of the sisters
  - Lucy and Sarah Adams; Ollivier, NY; signed, 1883; MS254.000442 (Box 2)
    Sarah and Lucy by Eisenmann, NY; notations on back are probably written by one of the sisters
  - Lucy Adams; Henshel, Chicago, 1887; MS254.000443 (Box 2)
    Unusual pose of Lucy, I think
  - Lucy and Sarah Adams; Ryder, Cleveland, 1887; MS254.000444 (Box 2)
    Lucy and Sarah in Cleveland, Ohio
  - Lucy and Sarah Adams; Ollivier, NY; trimmed, 1883; MS254.000445 (Box 2)
    Lucy and Sarah; Ollivier, NY
  - Lavinia Warren doll; Sarony, NY; Culver Pictures, 1870 -- 1890; MS254.000446 (Box 2)
    Doll claimed to be Lavinia Warren on the back; ex- Culver Pictures on back
  - Minnie Warren vignette; Broadbent and Phillips, Philadelphia; digital only, 1877; MS254.000447 (Box 2)
    Minnie passed away in 1878, so this is before that; original in Coenen Collection
  - Mrs. James Bump; Lavinia and Minnie's mother; Putnam, Middleboro; digital only, 1877; MS254.000448 (Box 2)
    Mother of Minnie and Lavinia
  - The only & Original Mrs. General Tom Thumb; Negretti & Gambra, Crystal Palace, London; signed on back; dated 1899, MS254.000449 (Box 2)
    Dated 1899
  - Lavinia Warren's family with Charles Stratton; Putnam, Middleboro; digital only, 1877; MS254.000450 (Box 9)
    This photograph was in the personal effects of Lavinia when she passed away; it was sold at auction in 1920; it came back to auction in 1985 and purchased by Christopher Coenen; original in Coenen Collection
  - Mounted photo of Tom Thumb with flag; Naramore, Bridgeport, Ct., 1860; MS254.000451 (Box 9)
    From a series of commercial views
  - Tom Thumb, Lavinia Warren, Sylvester Bleeker and Minnie Warren; digital only, 1870; MS254.000452 (Box 9)
    Tom, Lavinia and Minnie with their longtime manager and friend, Sylvester Bleeker; original in Coenen Collection
  - Nutshell Coach with Little Jim driving; notations on back ;Bradley and Rulofson, San Francisco; digital only, 1875; MS254.000453 (Box 9)
    Nutshell Coach, originally made for Commodore Nutt, but used by all the company; original coach may be in the Barnum Museum; original in Coenen Collection
  - Primo Magri, Lavinia Warren, Edwin Newell,Annie Nelson, Ernesto Magri, 1890; MS254.000454 (Box 9)
    The original photo taken by Putnam of Middleboro; after the death of Tom Thumb
  - Primo, Lavinia and Ernesto in Sanford, Me; Karmon, ph., 1902; MS254.000455 (Box 9)
    Notation on back says, "Saw the Trio, July 19-1902"
  - Primo, Lavinia and Ernesto; Gould, Saratoga, 1905; MS254.000456 (Box 9)
    Primo handing Lavinia flowers
  - Primo, Lavinia, Ernesto; Karmon, Sanford, Me., 1902; MS254.000457 (Box 9)
  - Primo, Lavinia, Ernesto; Karmon, Sanford, Me. variation, 1902; MS254.000458 (Box 9)
    variation of 407
  - Primo, Lavinia, Ernesto, Karmon, Sanford, Me.; variation 2, 1902; MS254.000459 (Box 9)
    Notation on back- "Aug. 22,1903
  - Primo, Lavinia, Ernesto: Gauvin & Gentzel, Halifax, N.S., 1900; MS254.000460 (Box 9)
    The trio in Nova Scotia
  - Primo, Lavinia, Ernesto; Patterson, Chicago; notations on back, 1904; MS254.000461 (Box 9)
    ""Received yr. 1904 at Wayne, Nebr., Mrs. Tom Thumb, her husband and her brother. Tom Thumb had passed away. They showed at the opera house at Wayne."
  - Primo, Lavinia and Ernesto; Halifax; variation of 410, 1900; MS254.000462 (Box 9)
    Variation of 410
  - Primo, Lavinia, and Ernesto; Halifax; variation 2 of 410, 1900; MS254.000463 (Box 9)
  - Millie-Christine McCoy; Siamese twins; Wendt, N, 1890; MS254.000464 (Box 9)
    Born into slavery, the twins eventually won their freedom and became popular; they brought Ernesto and Primo Magri to the US around 1878
  - Col. Ruth Goshen, Barnum giant; Bogardus, NY, 1875; MS254.000465 (Box 9)
    Goshen worked for Barnum but also worked with Lilliputian companies as "The Giant" in many performances
  - The Modern Mr. and Mrs. Tom Thumb, Wendt, NY, 1895; MS254.000466 (Box 9)
    There were many imitators who played on the Tom Thumb name
  - Portrait of Lavinia; newsphoto, 1912; MS254.000467 (Box 9)
    Portrait of an older Lavinia taken 12/1912 when she was 71
  - Portrait of Lavinia; altered newsphoto, 1912; MS254.000468 (Box 10)
    Portrait of an older Lavinia that has been altered for publication
  - St. Georges Hall, Liverpool, England, 1860; MS254.000469 (Box 9)
    St. Georges Hall opened in 1854; Tom Thumb probably played here